[Music]
welcome to this session about co-pilot
for finance with business Central
co-pilot for finance is a new product in
the Office 365 the Microsoft 365 Suite
of
applications it lives among what we call
the role based agents for work alongside
with co-pilot for sales and co-pilot for
service and it's a game changer for
finance professionals who work with
business Central and I'm going to
explain why before we go there let's
reflect on the role of a finance
function within a company in this day
and
age the primary goal of a finance
function is to provide Clarity to the
organization about the company's
finances and time to value is really the
most important parameter in this case
and times have changed Finance functions
used to be more sort of backward-looking
reporting based uh explaining what has
happened in the past how much this point
where the reporting is done and now move
to become more forward-looking
opportunity enabling business partners
that really enable the organization to
chase new goals or uh eliminate risk
this can only be done if the finance
function the finance department has sort
of a a realtime view of the company's
finances they need complete transparency
and Clarity to be able to bring these
numbers and opportunities to the
organization this requires a well oiled
machine for a finance function to work
that way so we need to ask ourselves as
users in a finance function and in
general are we spending our time
well well what we do know is that users
do a lot of task switching we use so
many applications in our daily life that
we toggle between applications and we we
we switch context and that's taxing for
our minds for for our brains even so
there been some interesting research
done published in the Harvard Business
Review that indicate that we switch
application so much that it actually
consumes about 4 hours per week on
average that is the time where we switch
between we tarle between applications
and reorient ourselves when we come back
to the to the task where we lost Focus
between because we had to move and
switch our Focus to this other
application this happened so much during
the day that we waste a lot of time if
we project this over a longer period of
time what we will see is that those 4
hours actually become 5 weeks per year
that's about 9% of the annual work time
that we spent switching task switching
context and reorient ourselves after we
lose focus and come back to what we were
actually doing what if there was a way
where we could stay in the zone and stay
in the flow of work well there is a way
and for finance professionals it's
called copilot for
finance as I said before this is a new
product that lives within the Microsoft
365 suite and really it empowers Finance
professionals to stream line their
operations to stay in the zone of work
and not leave the application that
they're working with by bringing in data
from other applications surfacing that
to them so they can take the best
decisions at that point in
time the cool new thing is that this is
now natively integrated with business
Central in Outlook first and foremost
but stay tuned um the first focus is to
empower people who work with accounts
receivables and first and foremost those
who work with collecting funds with
customers who haven't paid who have
outstanding
balances there's also an integration uh
well semi integration to excel as you
know business Central has very cool
integration to excel already with the
open and edit and Excel features and
copath for finance for Excel allows you
to reconcile to data sets and soon
interesting features will come that
allow you to do do variance analysis as
well for now this is a great companion
for the edit and Excel opening Excel
features in business
Central in Outlook even more interesting
things are happening now this is where
you would work as a collections manager
or as a collections team collecting
funds from your customers who have
outstanding balances here you have a new
companion a new sidecar in Outlook that
will help summarize a email threat you
have with a customer and surface
customer information and allow you to
update data back into business Central
now the great thing here is that you
would typically switch between Outlook
and BC to find the right information to
answer this customer or figure out
payment status or invoice status and so
on now you can do all of this within
Outlook and stay in the zone without
having to leave leave your favorite
application when comes to communicating
with
customers there's a lot more to come
here this is only the
beginning now one of the things to come
is the ability to manage your accounts
receivables from within teams if you go
to the road map right now and look at
what's planned for copal the finance
there are some really interesting things
coming among these things are
integration through teams which will
work with the same Erp data as the
current Outlook integration will do and
there's some interesting things here I
won't go through them all here but I
just want to call out that check out the
road map where you can figure out what's
um what's coming for copal
finance one thing in particular that I
like from the road map which you find
here at ak. msras planner is the
extensibility option basically what this
means is that if you have custom fields
on your entities in business Central you
can surf those in copal finance in the
experiences for example in Outlook so
and where you'll be using copal Studio
to do that authoring so for example you
have if you have an API on your
customers that exposes more Fields you
can Surface those as well or from your
invoices or from your letter entries for
example you can Surface those inside in
this case Outlook so this is just the
beginning if you want to learn more
about copal for finance and what it
empowers Finance professionals to do
especially with business Central check
out aka. ms/ copilot for
finance thank you for watching